<resources>
    <string name="app_name">HEALTH AND BEAUTY TIPS</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="splitEnds">1. Egg Yolk      \n
Using egg as a hair mask is one of the best and most effective remedies of all time. Eggs help cure your frizzy hair and give them a healthier shine. The egg yolk is the protagonist here. It has an adequate amount of protein that strengthens the strands of your hair and prevents any split ends. Egg also works as a moisturiser and conditioner for your hair.
                                        \n
How to Apply?                             \n

It is always better to team up the egg yolk with other ingredients to get remarkable results. One of the remedies is to mix egg yolk with two tablespoon each of olive oil, almond oil and honey. Apply this egg mask and keep it for about 30-45 minutes before washing it off with lukewarm water.
                                            \n\n

        2. Beer                                         \n

Applying beer is as good as drinking it. It supplies sugar and protein to your damaged hair follicles, thereby controlling split ends. It also helps in adding volume to your hair, apart from working as an amazing conditioner.
                                                  \n
How To Apply?                                       \n

Make sure you use flat beer on your hair. Beer with fizz may damage your hair. After shampooing your hair, just wash your hair with beer and keep it for 2-3 minutes before washing it off.
                                                      \n\n
3. Honey                                                  \n

Honey has always been a healer, working wonders for maintaining a healthy body, hair or skin. Honey has humectant, which prevents loss of moisture, thus rescuing you from getting a dry scalp. Consequently, it will also prevent split ends as it strengthens the hair follicles. It also helps in keep your hair scalp clean due to its anti-bacterial properties.
                                                            \n
How to Apply?                                                 \n

Using only honey and water can make your hair sticky and messy. A better way is to prepare a hair mask consisting of honey mixed with curd, olive oil and egg yolk (optional). Apply this mixture on your hair, including the scalp, and keep it for around 20-25 minutes before washing it off.
                                                                \n\n
4. Chamomile                                                        \n

Chamomile is a brilliant ingredient for curing dry and frizzy hair. Its antiseptic properties remove the dead cells to let your hair grow properly. Regular use of chamomile helps to prevent split ends as it keeps the hair scalp and hair clean.
                                                                      \n
How to Apply?                                                           \n

Giving your hair a nice rinse with chamomile tea can result in beautiful hair. All you need to do is soak two chamomile tea bags in boiling water and let it cool. Once the water has extracted its elements, rinse your hair using this water. You can use chamomile oil for massage too.
                                                                          \n
                                                                            \n
5. Black Lentils (Dal)                                                        \n

Black lentils are a wonderful source of proteins, iron, folic acid, phosphorus and fiber, among others. Folic acid is responsible for transporting oxygen from the blood to your hair follicles, thus improving the quality of your hair. You can apply and off course include a lot of it in your diet.
                                                                                \n
How to Apply?                                                                     \n

Make a coarse powder of half a cup of black lentils and one tablespoon of fenugreek seeds and blend it with half a cup of curd. Apply this thick paste on your hair and keep it for at least an hour before washing it off with a mild shampoo.
                                                                                    \n  \n
6. Ripe Papaya                                                                        \n

Papaya also consists of folic acid. Folic acid helps in improving the blood circulation in your scalp and hair. It also has vitamin A that enhances the production of sebum, which is natural oil present in the body. Papaya helps in keep your scalp and hair follicles moisturised, promoting hair growth and preventing spit ends and frizzy hair.
                                                                                          \n
How to Apply?                                                                               \n

All you need is to blend a raw papaya and yoghurt to make a thick paste. Apply it on your hair and wait for 30-45 minutes. Finally, wash it off using cold water.\n\n
7. Coconut Oil     \n

This is the most common, age-old recipe to prevent split ends. It helps in smoothening your hair and remove the dirt present on the scalp. It clearly combats all hair problems including split ends, dullness and hair fall.
                           \n
How to Apply?            \n

Without any additions, you just need to massage your hair and hair scalp with warm coconut oil and keep it for about 1-2 hours and wash it with tap water.
coconut oil                                                                  \n
Home remedies for split ends: Coconut hair oil helps in removing dirt from your hair
                                                                               \n\n
8. Aloe Vera                                                                       \n

Aloe Vera has always proved to be an excellent cure for damaged hair and split ends. It consists of proteolytic enzymes that dig out dead cells on the scalp, further letting your hair grow. It has antimicrobial and anti-inflammatory properties that keep your scalp cool and away from dirt, further promoting a healthy hair growth.
                                                                                     \n
How to Apply?                                                                          \n

All you need to do is to extract the gel out of 2-3 aloe vera leaves and apply it on your hair. It may be sticky and messy but worth it. Keep the gel for about 30-40 minutes and rinse it off. You can apply a mild shampoo after the application of gel.         \n
</string>
    <string name="dandruff">Dandruff Solution\n
        1. Tea Tree Oil
\nTea tree oil has antifungal properties. It can be used topically on your skin or scalp to mitigate any fungal infection that leads to flaky skin and dandruff.\n
You Will Need \n
2-3 drops of tea tree oil  \n
2-3 drops of sweet almond or jojoba oil  \n
What You Have To Do               \n
Mix a few drops of tea tree oil with sweet almond or jojoba oil.  \n
Dab a few drops of this mixture on a cotton pad and apply it to the scalp.\n
How Often You Should Do This                                                \n
Repeat 3-4 times a week.                                                      \n  \n
                                       2. Coconut Oil     \n
Coconut oil may combat fungal infections that can cause Malassezia . This, in turn, may reduce the occurrence of dandruff and flaky skin.
                 \n
You Will Need        \n
2 tablespoons of coconut oil \n

What You Have To Do            \n
Massage the coconut oil into your scalp. \n
Leave it on for about an hour before you wash it off with a mild shampoo.     \n
How Often You Should Do This \n
Repeat this 2 times a week. \n     \n

                                      3. Onion Juice     \n
Research has shown that onions are rich in phytochemical compounds that can help combat dandruff. Their topical application can help eliminate the flaking of skin and reduce the occurrence of dandruff (10).
             \n
You Will Need  \n
½ onion          \n
What You Have To Do\n
Blend an onion to extract its juice.
Strain it and apply generously to your scalp.
Leave it on for an hour and wash it off.  \n
How Often You Should Do This                \n
You can apply this juice to your scalp 2 times a week. \n    \n

4. Aloe Vera         \n
Aloe vera is a rich source of bioactive compounds that can be used to treat skin disorders. Extracts of aloe vera exhibit antifungal and antimicrobial properties that can help fight any fungal infection, including that causing dandruff (11).
                   \n
You Will Need        \n
Aloe vera gel          \n

What You Have To Do      \n
Massage some aloe vera gel into your scalp.
Massage in circular motions, ensuring the gel is absorbed into the scalp.
Wash off after 1 hour.                \n
How Often You Should Do This            \n
You can apply the gel at least 2 times a week.  \n\n

5. Probiotics            \n
Probiotic foods, such as yogurt, contain Lactobacillus paracasei that can help reduce dandruff. Research shows that Lactobacillus paracasei can help restore the normal balance of your scalp’s microbiome, thereby eliminating dandruff.
                          \n
You Will Need               \n
1 cup of probiotic yogurt     \n

What You Have To Do             \n
Consume a cup of probiotic yogurt.\n

How Often You Should Do This        \n
Do this every day.                    \n
                                          \n

6. Garlic                         \n
The primary bioactive constituents of garlic are ajoene and allicin. Their antifungal properties may help alleviate the fungal infection that can cause dandruff (15).
                                    \n
You Will Need                         \n
A few cloves of garlic                  \n
½ cup of olive oil                        \n
What You Have To Do                         \n
Peel and crush the garlic cloves.
Add the crushed garlic to a heated saucepan with olive oil.
Heat the mixture for 5 minutes and strain.
Allow it to cool down and apply it to your scalp.
Leave it on for 30-45 minutes before rinsing with water.\n
How Often You Should Do This                  \n
You can apply this oil 2 times a week.                    \n\n

7. Baking Soda        \n
Baking soda is commonly used as an antifungal agent (17). Hence, it may aid the treatment of dandruff.
                        \n
You Will Need             \n
2-3 tablespoons of baking soda\n

What You Have To Do             \n
Take a few tablespoons of baking soda and apply directly to wet hair.
Leave it on for about 2 minutes and wash off thoroughly.      \n
How Often You Should Do This      \n
You can do this 2 times a week.     \n\n

8. Lemon Juice       \n
Lemon juice is known to be a rich source of citric acid. The natural pH of scalp is 5.5, and citric acid-based shampoos or agents can help keep the pH of your scalp balanced (18). This may, in turn, help reduce the appearance of dandruff on your scalp.
                       \n
You Will Need            \n
2-3 tablespoons of freshly extracted lemon juice      \n
Cotton ball                                             \n
What You Have To Do                                       \n
Dab the lemon juice on a cotton ball and apply it to your scalp as a pre-shampoo treatment.
Leave it on for about 5-10 minutes and wash off with a mild shampoo.    \n
How Often You Should Do This                                              \n
You can do this 2 times a week.                                             \n\n

12. Green Tea        \n
Research shows that green tea is rich in polyphenols and epigallocatechin gallate (EGCG) that exhibit an inhibitory effect on fungal infections (19). This may eliminate any infection that can give rise to dandruff.
                       \n
You Will Need            \n
2-3 green tea bags         \n
Warm water                   \n
What You Have To Do            \n
Soak 2-3 green tea bags in warm water and strain it after it cools down.
Rinse your hair with this decoction and leave it in for about 10 minutes.
Wash off with a mild shampoo.      \n
How Often You Should Do This     \n
You can do this 2 times a week for a couple of months.
                                     \n\n

Prevention Tips                                                               \n
Dandruff is usually the direct result of dry scalp or skin. To prevent dandruff, you must:
                                                                                \n
Avoid washing your scalp very frequently as overusing commercially available shampoos can strip your scalp of natural moisture.     \n
Use mild shampoos as harsh chemicals can disturb the pH of your scalp and cause dryness of scalp and skin.                            \n
Drink lots of water as this can keep you hydrated and help maintain the natural moisture balance of your skin and scalp.                \n
Avoid using hair styling products, such as gels and sprays. These products cause build-ups and can aggravate dandruff."                   \n
    </string>
    <string name="hairfall">1. Vitamins    \n
Deficiencies in vitamins H, D, and E are associated with hair loss. Restoring such deficiencies by supplementing these vitamins may help restore hair growth . However, remember that over supplementation of these vitamins, as well as vitamin A, can cause severe side effects like alopecia.
                                             \n\n
2. Coconut Oil                                   \n
Coconut oil can penetrate deep into your hair shafts and prevent protein loss. This helps reduce hair damage and breakage often caused by physical trauma like styling and use of harsh products .
                                                   \n
You Will Need                                        \n
1-2 tablespoons of virgin coconut oil                  \n

What You Have To Do                                      \n
Massage virgin coconut oil gently into your scalp and hair.
Leave it on for at least an hour before rinsing it off with a mild cleanser.
Follow up with a conditioner.                              \n
How Often You Should Do This                                 \n
You may do this at least two times a week.                     \n
        \n\n
3. Amla (Indian Gooseberry)   \n
Amla (Emblica officinalis) possesses hair growth promoting activity. It has a proliferative effect on the dermal papilla cells in the hair follicles .
                                \n
You Will Need                     \n
Fresh amla juice (as required)      \n

What You Have To Do                   \n
Apply fresh amla juice to your scalp. Leave it on for 30 minutes.
Rinse it off using a mild cleanser.
Follow up with a conditioner.           \n
How Often You Should Do This              \n
You may do this 1-2 times a week.           \n
                                              \n
4. Yogurt                                       \n
Yogurt is a rich source of probiotics, which are known to lead to an acidic pH. An acidic pH can alter your hair cuticles, giving you a shinier mane and preventing damage that may trigger hair breakage and loss .
                                                  \n
You Will Need                                       \n
A bowl of probiotic-rich yogurt                       \n
What You Have To Do                                     \n
Consume a bowl of probiotic yogurt.                       \n

How Often You Should Do This                                \n
You can consume this once daily for best results.             \n
                                                                \n
5. Methi (Fenugreek)                                              \n
Fenugreek (Trigonella foenumgraecum) possesses hair growth promoting properties. It not only reduces hair loss significantly but also stimulates new hair growth .
                                                                    \n
You Will Need                                                         \n
½ cup of fenugreek seeds                                                \n
Water                                                                     \n
What You Have To Do                                                         \n
Soak half a cup of fenugreek seeds in water overnight.
Grind the soaked paste and apply it as a hair mask.
Leave it on for 30-60 minutes and rinse it off with water.                    \n
How Often You Should Do This                                                    \n
You may do this once a week.                                                      \n
                                                                                    \n
6. Onion Juice                                                                        \n
According to a study published in the Journal of Dermatology, the topical application of crude onion juice to the scalp can aid hair regrowth, especially in cases of alopecia areata .
                                                                                        \n
You Will Need                                                                             \n
½ onion                                                                                     \n
What You Have To Do                                                                           \n
Blend the onion and strain the mixture to obtain the juice.
Apply the juice to your scalp and leave it on for 30-60 minutes.
Rinse it off with water.                                                                        \n
How Often You Should Do This                                                                      \n
You may do this 1-2 times a week.                                                                   \n
                                                                                                      \n
7. Chinese Hibiscus                                                                                     \n
The leaves and flowers of Chinese hibiscus (Hibiscus rosa-sinensis) show hair growth promoting activities and can be used to deal with hair loss .
                                                                                                          \n
You Will Need                                                                                               \n
1-2 hibiscus flowers                                                                                          \n
5-6 hibiscus leaves                                                                                             \n
Coconut oil (as required)                                                                                         \n
What You Have To Do                                                                                                 \n
Blend the hibiscus flowers and leaves.
Add a little coconut oil to this mixture.
Apply it to your scalp and spread some to your hair.
Leave it on for 30-60 minutes.                                                                                        \n
Rinse it off with a mild shampoo and condition your hair.                                                               \n
How Often You Should Do This                                                                                              \n
You may do this once a week.                                                                                                \n
                                                                                                                              \n
8. Green Tea
Green tea contains a polyphenol called epigallocatechin-3-gallate (EGCG). EGCG stimulates the growth of the dermal papilla cells of the scalp and can help in the prevention as well as treatment of androgenetic alopecia .
                                                                                                                                \n
You Will Need                                                                                                                     \n
1 green tea bag                                                                                                                     \n
1 cup of hot water                                                                                                                    \n
What You Have To Do
Put a green tea bag in a cup of hot water.
Steep for 5-10 minutes and strain.
Allow the solution to cool a bit.
Drink the tea.                                                                                                                            \n
How Often You Should Do This                                                                                                            \n
You may drink this 1-2 times daily.                                                                                                       \n\n

9. Egg Yolk Mask                                                                                                                              \n
The water-soluble peptides in egg yolk possess hair growth stimulating properties that may be useful to treat hair loss .
                                                                                                                                                \n
You Will Need                                                                                                                                     \n
1 egg yolk                                                                                                                                          \n

What You Have To Do                                                                                                                                   \n
Whisk the egg yolk.
Apply it to your scalp and leave it on for at least 30 minutes.
Rinse it off using a fragrant shampoo and follow up with a conditioner.                                                                                 \n
How Often You Should Do This                                                                                                                              \n
You may do this once a week.                                                                                                                                \n\n

10. Henna         \n
Henna can help with hair regrowth when applied topically. It works almost as well as minoxidil (a drug used to treat hair loss) in treating hair fall caused by telogen effluvium.
                    \n
You Will Need         \n
1 cup of henna leaves   \n
Water (as required)       \n
What You Have To Do         \n
Blend the henna leaves with water to form a thick paste.
Apply the paste to your scalp and spread the remaining mixture through the length of your hair. Leave it on for an hour.
Rinse it off with water.
You may use any organic henna powder if fresh leaves aren’t available.   \n
How Often You Should Do This                \n
You may do this once in a week.               \n\n

11. Curry Leaves                                  \n
Curry leaves help in retaining the natural pigmentation of your hair while also stimulating hair growth .
                                                    \n
You Will Need                                         \n
A handful of curry leaves                               \n
½ cup of coconut oil                                      \n
What You Have To Do                                         \n
Add a handful of curry leaves to half a cup of coconut oil and heat it in a saucepan.
Once the mixture reduces to a black residue, switch off the stove and allow the oil to cool.
Strain the oil to remove the leaves from the mixture.
Apply the oil to your scalp and spread it through your hair. Leave it on for 30-60 minutes.
Rinse it off with a mild shampoo.
Follow up with a conditioner.                                 \n
How Often You Should Do This                                    \n
You may do this once every week.                                  \n\n

All these remedies can help reduce hair fall and may also reverse it if you follow them diligently. Remember, these remedies will take time to show results, so patience and consistency are key. In addition to the above remedies, here are some tips that may help prevent hair fall and damage.
                                                                        \n
How To Prevent Hair Fall                                              \n
Avoid tying your hair tight.                                              \n
Do not twist, rub, or pull your hair.                                       \n
Handle your hair gently while combing and washing.                            \n
Avoid using harsh treatments on your hair like curling irons, hot oil treatments, or hot rollers.   \n
Stop taking medications or supplements that could be contributing to hair fall.                       \n
Protect your hair from the damaging sun rays by using hats and scarves when you step out.               \n
Quit smoking.                                                                                             \n
Ask your doctor for a cooling cap if you are undergoing chemotherapy.                                       \n
    </string>
    <string name="adultHabits">Fitness Habits\n\n
1. Take a walk every day.                        \n

2. If you sit much of the day, stand up from your desk every 30 minutes and do 5 minutes of movement.
                                                   \n
3. Stretch for 5 minutes first thing in the morning or after your shower.
                                                     \n
4. Practice 10 minutes a day of aerobic exercise, like running, jumping jacks, dancing, or swimming.
                                                       \n
5. Practice 10 minutes a day of muscle-strengthening activities, working different muscle groups each day.
                                                         \n
6. Park your car farther away from entrances to work or stores.
                                                           \n
7. Take the stairs instead of the elevator.
                                                             \n
8. Run or jump on a rebounder for 30 minutes a day. It is really fun and great for your overall health!
                                                               \n
9. Find a running buddy and begin running every other day, starting with a walk/run if you are new to running.
\n
10. Take a fun exercise class like Zumba or Jazzercise.
  \n
11. Join a community sports team, like softball, basketball, soccer, or volleyball.
    \n
12. Find an outdoor habit you enjoy like biking, hiking, or inline skating.
      \n
13. Perform a specific number of sit-ups and/or push-ups every morning before your shower.
        \n
14. Walk or jog in place while watching TV, rather than sitting.
          \n
            \n
Healthy Eating Habits
\n\n
16. Drink an 8 ounce glass of water first thing in the morning.
    \n
17. Keep a full water bottle on your desk and drink water throughout the day. \n
18. Substitute one unhealthy food choice for a healthy food (ie: instead of snacking on chips, eat carrots with hummus).
   \n
19. Add one additional serving of vegetables to one of your daily meals.
     \n
20. Increase dark green leafy vegetables in your diet like kale, spinach, swiss chard, and mustard greens.
       \n
21. Drink a cup of green or white tea every day.
         \n
22. Eat smaller meals more frequently throughout the day. Having six smaller meals rather than three large ones a day will help you manage hunger and manage your weight.
           \n
23. Substitute a lean protein like chicken or fish for red meat once a week.
             \n
24. Substitute fruit for a high calorie, sugary dessert.
               \n
25. Clean out your pantry and get rid of all processed snacks.
                 \n
26. Go to the grocery store on a full stomach only.
                   \n
27. Eat breakfast every day, including a combination of complex carbohydrates, fiber, protein and a small amount of fat.
                     \n
28. Reduce your serving portions at lunch or dinner by half. Sit for 15 minutes before adding more food to your plate to see if you are still hungry.
                       \n
29. Once or twice a week, eat a 100% plant-based dinner.
                         \n
30. Switch from white, bleached breads and grains (pasta, rice) to whole grains.
                           \n
31. Begin a practice of eating more mindfully and slowly. Take twice as long to eat your meal.
                             \n
32. Reduce the amount of alcohol you drink. Consider having it only on weekends.
                               \n
33. Cook with healthy oils like olive oil or coconut oil rather than butter.
\n
34. Choose air popped popcorn as an evening snack rather than chips or sweets.
  \n\n
Good Habits Of Mind
\n\n
35. Practice awareness of your negative thoughts during the day.
    \n
36. Once you are aware of your negative thought patterns, practice interrupting the thoughts and thinking or doing something positive.
      \n
37. Take 5 minutes a day to contemplate everything you are grateful for.
        \n
38. Write down positive affirmations about the way you want your day or a particular situation to unfold and say them out loud to yourself in the morning.
          \n
39. Spend five minutes mentally reliving a happy memory including as much detail as you can remember.
            \n
40. Challenge your mental assumptions about people or expected outcomes.
              \n
41. Practice a mental mind shift where you accept you are capable of far more than you previously believed.
                \n
42. Review any recent or past failures or mistakes for a few minutes a day, and think about what you learned from them and how you can apply what you learned.
                  \n
43. Mentally challenge yourself during a project or task to push yourself just beyond your comfort zone or a bit longer when you want to quit.
                    \n
44. Take up a mentally challenging hobby like crossword puzzles, Suduko, or other brain games to keep your brain active.
                      \n
45. Memorize a poem or piece of prose every day.
                        \n
46. Every day, substitute positive and uplifting reading material, TV shows, and other media for negative, depressing mental input.
                          \n
47. During a daily task or work project, stop before proceeding and ponder a new, more creative way to approach or implement the work.
                            \n
48. Spend 5-10 minutes a day just imagining and daydreaming about something positive you want to do.
                              \n
49. When you must make a decision, practice giving yourself a time limit for contemplation and research, and then decide even if you are not completely sure.
                                \n
50. When you make a decision during the day, use critical thinking skills using self-examination, review of possible outcomes, and consideration of alternatives.
                                  \n\n
Spiritual/Emotional Habits:            \n\n

51. Begin a practice of morning or evening meditation, prayer, or contemplation, starting with just five minutes a day.
\n
52. At defined times during your workday (mid-morning, after lunch, late afternoon), take five minutes to close your eyes and practice diaphragmatic breathing.
  \n
53. Practice noticing and identifying your emotions when you feel them without judging them.
    \n
54. Every day, begin the morning by putting your life and problems into perspective by contemplating the size of the Earth, our solar system, our galaxy, and the universe.
      \n
55. Begin a daily habit practice of walking meditation.
        \n
56. Begin to pay attention to the foods you eat and how they affect your emotions (ie: coffee making you anxious, sweets making you sleepy, etc.)
          \n
57. When you feel stressed during the day, make yourself stop for 5 minutes to identify the source of the stress.
            \n
58. During the day, notice how the people around you make you feel — whether they energize and uplift you or drain you.
              \n
59. When you experience negative emotions (sadness, anxiety, anger, etc.), practice having your “higher self” step outside of the emotions to remind you they are temporary and do not define you.
                \n
60. Create the habit of spending time in nature every day and mindfully appreciating the beauty around you.
                  \n
61. In whatever you are doing, mindfully redirect your focus to the present moment and the task at hand.
                    \n
62. Practice a habit of serving others or performing an act of kindness every day.
                      \n
63. When you have negative feelings, begin to notice the thoughts that preceded the feelings and actively change the thoughts.
                        \n
64. Read or watch something that makes you laugh out loud every day.
\n
65. Seek out one or two positive, upbeat people to spend time with every day.</string>
    <string name="acne">\n1. Wash Your Face Properly  Thorough cleansing is the backbone of any skin care routine. Use a mild and non-comedogenic cleanser to clean your face twice daily – once in the morning and once before going to bed. Cleanse your face if you sweat heavily. However, avoid washing it just because it feels oily. Use a blotting paper to remove the oil from your skin. Also, use warm water while washing to open up the pores. \n\n   2. Know Your Skin Type :\n  This is important as it will help you choose the right skin care products for your skin type. Products that are suitable for oily skin are not ideal for dry skin. Oily skin is the most prone to pimples because the sebaceous glands are overactive and produce a lot of sebum. Combination skin is also prone to pimples on the T-zone.  \n \n 3. Keep Your Skin Moisturized :\n  Moisturizing your skin is essential for pimple prevention. However, avoid moisturizers that contain chemicals and synthetic fragrances. Always go for non-comedogenic moisturizers so that your skin does not feel dry after every wash.  \n\n  4. Use Acne Medication  :\n There are over-the-counter medications available in drugstores that you can use to treat acne and pimples. Consult a dermatologist before taking any medicines. Also, make sure you follow the instructions properly.  \n\n  5. Drink Water (A Lot Of It!) :\n  When your body is dehydrated, it signals your skin to produce more oil to keep it moisturized. This increases inflammation and worsens acne.  \n \n 6. Use Makeup Wisely  :\n You may be tempted to cover up your acne and scars with makeup. However, makeup can clog your pores further and aggravate your condition. When using makeup, choose non-comedogenic and non-greasy formulas. Also, avoid heavy foundations and concealers. \n\n   7. Avoid Touching The Pimple  :\n Your fingers are home to germs and bacteria that might get transferred to your skin. Hence, do not squeeze, touch, or scratch the pimple. \n \n  8. Keep Yourself Sun-Safe \n  Long-term sun exposure dehydrates your skin and makes it produce more oil, causing blocked pores and breakouts. Carry an umbrella and use sunscreen if you are heading out.   \n\n 9. Check Your Diet :  What you eat reflects on your skin. Hence, be mindful of what you are putting on your plate. A review published in the Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology suggests that certain foods can worsen acne. Foods with a high glycemic index, such as baked goodies, chips, soft drinks, and those made with white flour, can aggravate acne. Dairy products were found to trigger acne breakouts in some cases.   \n\n 10. No Scrubbing :  Avoid using face scrubs if you have acne. Avoid cleaning your face with cloth pads or washcloths. Scrubbing already irritated skin causes further inflammation and exacerbates pimples or acne breakouts.  \n\n  11. Check Your Hair Care Products :  Hair care products (shampoos, conditioners, and styling products) contain chemicals and oils that may clog the pores and cause acne and pimples near the hairline, forehead, and neck. This type of acne is often called Acne cosmetica. Use products that are non-comedogenic, oil-free, and non-acnegenic. Also, after using any hair product, wash the scalp well to clear any residue. \n\n   12. Reduce Stress :  Stress can also cause pimples and acne. Try to cut down your stress levels by doing meditation or any other activity that keeps you happy and stress-free. \n \n  13. Keep The Facial Accessories Clean  : If you use makeup brushes, beauty blenders, facial cleaning brushes, make sure to keep them clean. Using unclean accessories that contain germs may cause pimples and acne. Hence, wash them thoroughly after every use.</string>
    <string name="stay_fit">Excercises for Women:\n

1. Jumping rope                                      \n
The burn: 667–990 calories/hour if you are jumping at 120 skips per minute
The bonus burn: Try using a weighted jump rope to engage your arms and shoulders even more.
                                                       \n
2. Running Up Hill/Stair Sprints\n
The burn: 639–946 calories/hour
The bonus burn: You want to sprint at a pace that you can only maintain for about 20 seconds, and follow that with a recovery run at half of the intensity of the sprint and double the time.
                                  \n
3. Kickboxing                       \n
The burn: 582–864 calories/hour
The bonus burn: Make sure you keep the rest periods between rounds of jabs and kicks super short. Aim for 30 seconds of rest for every 90 seconds of sparring.
                                      \n
4. Cycling intervals                    \n
The burn: 568–841 calories/hour
The bonus burn: Adding high intensity intervals throughout a steady state or low-intensity ride will increase the afterburn even more.
                                          \n
5. Running                                  \n
The burn: 566–839 calories/hour at a 10-minute mile pace
The bonus burn: Run at a steady state pace (i.e. a 7 out of 10 in terms of effort), and you’ll continue to burn extra calories over the rest of the day.
                                              \n
6. Kettlebell circuit                           \n
The burn: 554–822 calories/hour
The bonus burn: Tamir says that a HIIT circuit using kettlebells can keep the afterburn going for 36 hours after you leave the gym. To get the best results, make sure you’re not stopping to rest between each move.
                                                  \n
7. Stationary bike                                  \n
The burn: 498–738 calories/hour (at a vigorous pace)
The bonus burn: To get the most afterburn, Tamir says to start with 10 seconds of intense pedaling (100 RPMs or more) and 50 seconds of rest. Then, move to 15 seconds of sprints and 45 seconds of rest, and do 20 seconds of sprints 40 seconds of rest after that. Do not forget to turn up the resistance as you progress!
                                                      \n
8. Rowing machine                                       \n
The burn: 481–713 calories/hour at 150 watts, which you can check on the machine
The bonus burn: To get maximum torching power, row in super-fast, one-minute intervals (150 watts), and take 30- to 60-second active rest periods by alternating between squats, pushups, and planks.
                                                          \n
9. Stairs                                                   \n
The burn: 452–670 calories/hour when going 77 steps per minute
The bonus burn: To up the ante, hold a one- to five-pound dumbbell in each hand to get your upper body fired up, too.
                                                              \n    \n
Exercises for Men:                                              \n

1. Walking                                                        \n
Walking is one of the best exercises for weight loss — and for good reason.It’s convenient and an easy way for beginners to start exercising without feeling overwhelmed or needing to purchase equipment. Also, it’s a lower-impact exercise, meaning it doesn’t stress your joints.
                                           \n
2. Jogging or running                        \n
Jogging and running are great exercises to help you lose weight.Jogging and running are great exercises for weight loss that are easy to incorporate into your weekly routine. They can also help burn belly fat, which is linked to many chronic diseases.
                                               \n
3. Cycling                                       \n
Cycling is a popular exercise that improves your fitness and can help you lose weight.Although cycling is traditionally done outdoors, many gyms and fitness centers have stationary bikes that allow you to cycle while staying indoors.
                                                   \n
4. Weight training                                   \n
Weight training is a popular choice for people looking to lose weight.Weight training can help you lose weight by burning calories during and after your workout. It may also help you build muscle mass, which raises your resting metabolic rate — the number of calories your body burns at rest.
                                                       \n
5. Interval training                                     \n
Interval training, more commonly known as high-intensity interval training (HIIT), is a broad term that refers to short bursts of intense exercise that alternate with recovery periods.Typically, a HIIT workout lasts 10–30 minutes and can burn a lot of calories.One study in 9 active men found that HIIT burned 25–30% more calories per minute than other types of exercises, including weight training, cycling, and running on a treadmill .
                                                           \n
6. Swimming                                                  \n
Swimming is a fun way to lose weight and get in shape.Harvard Health estimates that a 155-pound (70-kg) person burns approximately 233 calories per half hour of swimming.How you swim appears to affect how many calories you burn. Per 30 minutes, a 155-pound (70-kg) person burns 298 calories doing backstroke, 372 calories doing breaststroke, 409 calories doing butterfly, and 372 calories treading water.
                                                               \n
7. Yoga                                                          \n
Yoga is a popular way to exercise and relieve stress.While it’s not commonly thought of as a weight loss exercise, it burns a fair amount of calories and offers many additional health benefits that can promote weight loss.Harvard Health estimates that a 155-pound (70-kg) person burns around 149 calories per 30 minutes of practicing yoga.
    \n\n</string>
    <string name="blackheads">  Do’s for blackheads \n\n
Cleansing:\n Special scrubs for gently exfoliating the face can help. Look for those that are fragrance-free and for sensitive skin, and avoid anything that makes your skin overly dry. Various products are available to purchase online.
While it is important to dry up the skin by decreasing excessive oil production, drying it too much may make matters worse due to stimulating the extra production of oil by the glands.
                   \n\n
Make-up and cosmetics:\n Use non-comedogenic products that do not clog pores instead should keep the pores clear and open and reduce the buildup of dead skin. Non-comedogenic makeup is available to purchase online from various brands.
                        \n\n
Rest and relaxation: \nGetting enough rest and avoiding stress can also help, as stress can trigger sebum production. Exercise can help reduce stress.
                       \n\n
Food:\n Research has not confirmed that cutting out fries or chocolate either will or will not reduce acne, but a healthful, balanced diet with plenty of fresh fruit and vegetables is beneficial for overall health. It may reduce the risk of skin lesions becoming infected.
       \n\n
Don’ts for blackheads     \n\n
Hormonal triggers can make blackheads unavoidable, but some factors can increase the risk or make them worse.
                              \n\n
Squeezing:\n Avoid squeezing blackheads, even with a metal blackhead remover, as this can irritate the skin and make the problem worse.
            \n\n
Steaming: \nA steam bath has long been recommended as a treatment for blackheads, on the basis that it “opens the pores.” However, this has not been confirmed by research. Some people find it makes the problem worse.
            \n\n
Scrubbing: \nThis can worsen the problem. Scrubbing removes sebum. The sebaceous glands then work harder to replace the sebum, leading to more blockages and the risk of inflammatory acne.
      \n\n
Removers:\n Removal strips, masks, and vacuums should be used with caution, as these can irritate and damage the skin if misused.
           \n\n
Makeup and cosmetics:\n Avoid oil-based makeups and skin care products.
                   </string>
    <string name="contact_lenses">       1. Wash Your Hands
\nBefore you handle the contact lenses, always wash your hands using water and soap. Rinse them thoroughly and then either air-dry them or use a lint-free towel to pat them dry. This makes sure no germs and bacteria are transferred to the lens from your fingers.
\n\n
2. Use The Lenses As Per Instructions
\nAvoid sleeping with the contact lenses on. Wear them and use them as per the instructions given to you by your ophthalmologist. Avoid using expired lens solution for cleaning them and replace them at regular intervals.
\n\n
3. Store Them Properly
\nAlways use the sterile solution provided with the contact lens to store them. Never use tap water to rinse them or store them in saline solution. Also, do not wet them with your saliva. This transfers millions of bacteria to the lenses, which can easily infect your eyes.
\n\n
4. Quit Smoking
\nWhile quitting smoking is good for your overall health, if you wear contact lenses, you should definitely quit. This is because compared to nonsmokers, smokers are more vulnerable to eye issues.
\n\n
5. Avoid Using Decorative Lenses
\nI know you are fascinated by the colored lenses available in the market, but avoid using the tinted lenses sold in decorative shops. These lenses can cause irreparable damage to your vision and eyes.

And above all, do not ignore even the slightest signs of discomfort in your eyes. Visit the ophthalmologist to get a comprehensive eye examination done every year. Even if these habits and tips seem too basic, these small steps go a long way in protecting your vision and eyes.   \n\n
  </string>
    <string name="dark_circle"> Dark circles remedy:\n\n      1. Use Tea Bags
\nApply cool tea bags over closed eyes. Don’t use herbal tea bags because most aren’t as effective as the black tea bags.

\n\n      2. Chilled Cotton Balls
\nDip cotton balls in cold water and keep them on your eyes for 5-10 minutes.

\n\n      3. Sliced Cucumber\nCucumbers work wonders for tired eyes. Place two slices of cucumber over your eyes and rest for a while. They not only have cooling properties but also help lighten dark circles.

You can also extract cucumber juice, dip cotton pads in it, and place them on your eyes.

\n\n      4. Tomato, Turmeric, Lime Juice
\nMix a teaspoon of tomato pulp with a pinch of turmeric and half a teaspoon of lime juice. Apply on the eyelids and around the dark circles. Let it dry and then wash it off.

\n\n      5. Almond Oil And Lime Juice For Beautiful Eyes
\nAlternate hot and cold compresses on your eyes for 10 minutes and then apply a mixture of a teaspoon of almond oil and half a teaspoon of lime juice. Let it stay overnight.

\n\n      6. Rose Water
\nThe rejuvenating factor of rose water is extremely useful in diminishing dark circles. Dip cotton pads in rose water and place them on your eyes for 10-15 minutes. Do this every day to get rid of dark circles.

       \n\n  </string>
    <string name="dry_skin">Dry skin:                  \n\n
1. You guys can use a great face pack made of mashed ripe avocado and ripe banana which works wonders for dry skin.
\n\n
2. Exfoliation is important for all skin types but especially important for dry skin types, exfoliation with mild granulated exfoliation cream or even sugar granules (finely granulated) is good for exfoliation.
\n\n
3. After exfoliation, skin will need moisture and hydration, use a deep nourishing cream or lotion or just plain simple glycerin mixed with water.
    \n\n
4. Occasionally you can do a deep nourishing treatment to your skin if it’s not sensitive to oil and rashes, with one vit E capsule oil to 2tbsp olive oil and use on face with cotton ball, before using this, do not forget to wash face with warm water and face wash and pat dry , then use this.
        \n\n
5. You can also use the cream of boiled milk (malai) on to face as mask and leave it on for 10 minutes then wash off with plain water, it’s great for dry skin.
            \n\n
6. Not to mention 8-10 glasses of water and fruits like ripe papaya, ripe banana, and mangoes are good for you.\n">
           </string>
    <string name="gray_hair">    1.Coconut oil. Every other day, before bed, massage coconut oil onto your hair and scalp. The next morning, wash your hair as usual.
\n\n2.Ginger: Every day, eat a teaspoon of fresh grated ginger mixed with 1 tablespoon of honey.
\n\n3.Blackstrap molasses: Every other day, eat a tablespoon of blackstrap molasses (from sugarcane juice, not from beet sugar); it’s believed to reverse the graying process.
\n\n4.Amla: Drink six ounces of fresh amla juice every day or massage your hair with amla oil one time each week. Amla is also known as Indian gooseberry.
\n\n5.Black sesame seeds: Two to three times a week, eat a tablespoon of black sesame seeds to slow down and possibly reverse the graying process.
\n\n6.Ghee:Twice a week, massage your hair and scalp with pure ghee (clarified butter).
\n\n7.Amaranth : Three times a week, apply fresh amaranth juice to your hair.
\n\n8.Wheatgrass juice : Drink one to two ounces of fresh wheatgrass juice every day or add 1 tablespoon of wheatgrass powder daily to your soups and smoothies.
\n\n9.Onion : Blend an onion in a blender and then use a strainer so that you’re left with the juice. Twice a week, rub this juice into your scalp, leaving it in place for 30 minutes and then shampooing as usual.
\n\n10.Carrot juice : Drink 8 ounces of carrot juice every day.
\n\n11.Catalase: Eat foods rich in the enzyme catalase such as:garlic,cabbage,sweet potato,kale,broccoli,almonds
\n\n12.Curry leaves : Make a paste of ¼ cup of curry leaves and ½ cup of yogurt. Apply it to your hair and scalp and then wash it off after 30 minutes. Repeat two to three times a week.
\n\n13.Ashwagandha : Take an ashwagandha supplement with food. Ashwagandha is also known as Indian ginseng.
\n\n14.Almond oil: Mix together equal parts of almond oil, lemon juice, and amla juice. Massage the mixture into your hair and scalp. Follow this routine two times a day for three months.
\n\n15.Rosemary : Fill ⅓ of an 8-ounce jar with dried rosemary and then fill the jar to the top with extra virgin olive oil. Leave the jar in a sunny place for four to six weeks, shaking it every few days. After six weeks, use it as a hair oil.
\n\n  </string>
    <string name="lips">1. Do not Touch or Lick your Lips:\n
Lips do not have any protection of their own, which means that each time you touch them or lick them, they are getting directly affected.

It is essential that you do not do anything that will make the problem worse.

Never lick your lips. It might feel good for the moment and also feel hydrating for your lips. But once the saliva evaporates, it will leave the lips even drier. The enzymes in the saliva are simply too harsh on your delicate lips.
                                                \n\n
The next thing to never do is breathe with your mouth open. Imagine how much of the moisture must get stripped away with all that dry air blowing over it.

And the last in this segment, is but obvious. Don’t kiss anyone with any infections on their lips. For it takes absolutely no time for an infection to spread to any cracks on your lips too!
                                                \n\n
2. Follow Healthy Diet Plan:                        \n
A good diet is essential not just for your skin but even for your lips.

Vitamins and other nutrients reflect directly on the condition of your lips. It is essential that you stay on a healthy diet to have lovely lips!
                                          \n\n
3. Stay Hydrated By Drinking Lot of Water:    \n
Staying hydrated is one of the most important things when it comes to healthy lips. Just as your skin needs to be kept hydrated from the inside, so do your lips.
                                                \n\n
4. Remove Makeup:                                   \n
Your lips need to be able to breathe by being clear.

Make sure you remove all traces of makeup from your lips before you sleep.
Use a damp cotton ball and wipe your lips clean.      \n\n
5. Keep Your Lips Hydrated Overnight:                     \n
While we are awake we know when our lips dry out, but this could be a problem when you are asleep.

The air around you tends to dry out your lips while you sleep.

Make sure you use a heavy or hydrating lip cream or some petroleum jelly before you sleep.
You can also use cream or raw milk for the same or even ghee (clarified butter).\n\n
6. Massage your Lips:                                       \n
You can use some nourishing oils to massage your lips for about 5 minutes every day.

This improves the blood circulation in your lips and ensures that they get the nutrients that are needed.
                                                                                    \n\n
7. Scrub Your Lips:                                                                     \n
Scrubbing your lips is important to ensure that they stay healthy and soft. Removing dead skin cells is a must to make sure that your lips don’t succumb to any infection.

Use any mild scrub that is available in the market for lips
Alternatively, you can make your own lip scrub at home with some rock sugar.              \n\n
8. Always Carry a Lip Balm:                                                                   \n
You never know when your lips tend to start drying out. Make sure you have a good creamy and hydrating lip balm with you even while you are traveling.
\n\n
9. Use Lipsticks when Stepping Out: \n
Yes, the good news is that it is good to use some lipstick before you step out.

Since, the lips have no natural protection, wearing a lipstick will help you add a layer to them.

Using lipsticks protects your lips from the sun, dry air, dirt and other outside factors.\n\n
         </string>
    <string name="oily_skin"> Oily skin:\n\n
1. Cut slices of tomato and rub on to skin, it’s great as a toner and also as an astringent.
\n\n
2. The same you can do to lessen the oiliness and brighten up sallow complexion created due to oiliness by rubbing slices of cold apple on your cheeks and forehead.
    \n\n
3. Egg beaten up with soaked and ground (or parboiled and ground) oats and use it as a pack on to oily skin to remove excess oiliness.
        \n\n
4. Raw milk can be used directly as a cleanser with cotton balls on to oily skin.
            \n\n
5. You can use a mixture of raw milk with freshly squeezed lemon juice mixed into it and apply with cotton ball to cleanse face , but if you do use this mixture , then keep it for 5-10 minutes at least before rinsing with water again since lemon helps reducing excess oiliness.
                \n\n
6. Drink fresh fruit juices , especially citrus fruits and apple juices , or even raw papaya juice like half a cup at an interval of two days are good , plus not to mention 8-10 glasses of water minimum to keep skin hydrated and toxin free.
                    \n\n
7.Wash face with a oil removing face wash or a face wash or mild soap with tea tree oil and wash at least 3 times a day like morning, at bathing and before going to bed, or morning, evening and before going to bed.
  \n\n
8. Keep tissues with you and fresh freshener when you go out, do not let dirt and grime accumulates on skin.\n\n
         </string>
</resources>
               